(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone and
welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- My name is Katherine and today we're
talking about sports and outdoor activities.
- That's right, we are taking a look
at a lot of different adventure sports.
So they're not just regular
sports like tennis or soccer.
These are more dangerous sports.
- That's right, so
adventure sports is the topic.
This is intermediate level.
Let's check out the dialogue
and we'll be back in a moment.
(upbeat music)
- Welcome to Adventure Tours.
How may I help you?
- I want to book a tour
with adventure sports.
- Excellent, our company
has more than 10 years
of experience in the adventure
tourism and sports field.
Let me show you some options.
This is our most popular choice.
Our river guides will
take you in a whitewater
rafting trip followed by
a ride in a hot air balloon.
- I don't really think
I'm ready to throw myself
down a river full of jagged
rocks and a rubber boat
or go up in the air in a wicker
basket held up by an oversized balloon.
What else do you have?
- Well, in that case, we can take you
hang gliding with one of
our experienced instructors.
It's the closest you can get to flying.
- What?
- You mean strap myself to a flimsy kite?
- No, thank you.
Next?
- Okay, well why don't you tell me a
little bit more about what you would like?
- We have everything from mountain
biking to rock climbing to street loose.
- I'm thinking something
exciting but safer.
- I have the perfect option.
This package will take you on a hiking
trip through the Himalayas for three days.
And afterwards there's
a dog sledding journey.
That's more like it.
(upbeat music)
- All right, we're back.
So obviously this tour agency or tour
operator has a lot of different options.
A lot of them exciting so
why don't we take a look
at some of those on language take away?
- Language take away.
- So the first one has to do with water.
This is called white water rafting.
- That's right, so white water rafting.
Now rafting means that you go in a raft.
- That's right, it's a
special kind of boat.
Not a wooden boat, not a
big boat you see in the ocean.
- This is a special boat for rivers, maybe.
- That's right, it's an
inflatable rubber boat.
So he also described it as a rubber boat.
- Okay, rubber is the
material it's made out of.
- That's right, so you
go in this boat in a river.
And it's called white water because it has,
what the, because it has rapids.
So the river is moving very
quickly and you can see that it's
a little bit dangerous to go
swimming in a river like this.
- That's right, so when
the water goes really
fast or when it hits
some rocks, it goes,
the color changes from
being blue or brown to white.
And that's why it's white water rafting.
- That's right.
- And it's very, very
scary and very dangerous.
- That's right, but very exciting.
So that's considered an adventure sport.
And then the trip was followed
by a ride in a hot air balloon.
Well, everyone's seen balloons before.
Sometimes we give children balloons
at the fair or maybe for their birthday.
Balloons are basically
rubber filled with air.
But a hot air balloon is a very special
kind of mode of transportation, actually.
You can travel in a hot air balloon.
- That's right, it's a big, big
balloon that has a basket under it.
And the person actually
described it as a wicker basket.
A wicker is the material
that's used in the basket, right?
- That's right, you can have
wicker furniture, like wicker chairs.
It's just a way to basically make furniture
out of this kind of
bark or natural material.
- So a hot air balloon is a very big
balloon and it's filled with hot air,
usually by some sort
of fire that's under it.
And because it's filled with
hot air, it goes up in the air.
And as you say, you can
use it as transportation.
Maybe to go very long
distances carried by the wind
because there's no real way of giving
a direction or just for fun, that's right.
It's another dangerous, but
less dangerous kind of sport.
But after that, we actually have one that,
I think you have some experience
with it's called hangliding.
- That's right, hangliding is another type
of sport and also a type of flying sport.
And basically you get on a hanglider.
Okay, so if you've seen this before,
you'll know that it looks like
someone is wearing wings.
- That's right.
It's a big kite that you wear.
- Uh-huh, it's a big kite.
It kind of looks like
a triangle, like a kite.
And you fly in it.
So it has no motor, it has not like
the hot air balloon, it has no fire.
So you just basically glide, you just
sail through the air, the atmosphere.
- Sounds very peaceful.
- It is.
- But they say that you
should go with an instructor.
So what kind of instructor
does this tour company offer?
- That's right.
Our operator talked about
taking you on a hanglider
trip with one of our
experienced instructors.
- So experienced is the key word here.
You want someone who
has done this many times
before, someone who
knows what they are doing.
- That's right.
So an experienced
instructor is a person that has,
as you say, a lot of
experience or is a professional.
So that's an experienced instructor.
- Right, you could even say, you know,
I want to take flying lessons
with an experienced pilot.
- Right, or you can even
talk about maybe a chef.
He is a very experienced chef.
He's been a chef for a long time.
- That's right.
So hangliding and our final
sport, very exciting as well.
We are going dog sledding.
- Okay, so this is basically a winter sport
or a sport that you do in snowy places.
You stand or sit on a
sled and a team of dogs.
So that means many dogs
pull you across the snow.
- That's right.
So you go on a sled, which
is basically usually made out
of plastic or wood, and this
is to go on top of the snow.
And as you say, a team of dogs pull you.
I think you can see this in movies.
This is kind of like the mode of transportation
in places where there are no roads,
there are no other ways of getting
places that you just get pulled by dogs.
- Like Alaska or the Arctic Circle.
Some are very, very far north.
- Exactly.
So a lot of great adventure
sports, very exciting.
I think it's time for us to
listen to the dialogue again.
And we'll be back in a bit with
language takeaway part two.
- Welcome to Adventure Tours.
How may I help you?
- I want to book a tour
with adventure sports.
- Excellent.
Our company has more
than 10 years of experience
in the adventure
tourism and sports field.
Let me show you some options.
This is our most popular choice.
Our river guides will
take you in a whitewater
rafting trip followed by
a ride in a hot air balloon.
- I don't really think
I'm ready to throw myself
down a river full of jagged
rocks in a rubber boat
or go up in the air in a wicker
basket held up by an oversized balloon.
What else do you have?
- Well, in that case, we can take you hang
gliding with one of our
experienced instructors.
It's the closest you can get to flying.
- What?
- You mean strap myself to a flimsy kite?
No, thank you.
Next?
- Okay, well, why don't you tell me a
little bit more about what you would like?
We have everything from mountain
biking to rock climbing to street loose.
- I'm thinking something
exciting, but safer.
- I have the perfect option.
This package will take you on a hiking
trip through the Himalayas for three days.
And afterwards, there's
a dog sledding journey.
That's more like it.
- All right, we're back.
So now we're going to take a
look at three quick adjectives
that we saw in this dialogue
on language takeaway part two.
- Language takeaway.
- This first adjective is
something I am not a fan of.
Let me just say, if you ever
go rafting and you see rocks,
you want to avoid or you want
to stay away from jagged rocks.
- That's right.
So the adjective jagged refers to
maybe sharp or they can cut you, right?
- That's right.
So something that is jagged is not smooth.
It's the opposite of smooth.
- That's right.
So maybe you've seen some
rocks that are very pointier
or that have things that
can easily hurt you or cut you.
Those are jagged rocks.
- Broken glass can have jagged edges.
And that means you want to avoid
touching it 'cause it can hurt you.
- Exactly.
So jagged is a way of describing something
that's maybe sharp pointier or
very dangerous that can cut you.
And then moving on when we
were talking about the hot air balloon,
this person very cleverly
said that he doesn't want to go
up in the air in a basket
held by an oversized balloon.
- Okay, so he's exaggerating.
Like he said, he's being clever or silly.
He's just afraid of the balloon.
But basically he's saying
an oversized balloon
is a very, very, very big
or unnaturally big balloon.
- Right. So bigger than normal.
So an oversized balloon would be
a balloon that's bigger than normal.
Or maybe I've seen an oversized...
- In the early 1990s, I remember a clothing trend.
A lot of people like to
wear oversized t-shirts.
- That's right.
So t-shirts that were way
too big for you or maybe
unnaturally big, those
would be oversized t-shirts.
- Like XXL.
- Exactly.
All right.
And our final adjective when he was talking
about hangliding, he
said that he's not ready to
go up in the air to
strapped to a flimsy kite.
- Okay, so the key word here is flimsy.
We already talked about a kite.
It's something that flies in the air.
But something that's flimsy
is not very stable or sturdy.
- That's right.
So it doesn't seem like it's very solid.
So if you have a kite.
- So a normal airplane is very sturdy.
But a paper airplane is very flimsy.
- Exactly.
- Then it moves around a lot.
You can't control it.
- Exactly.
So it's not very solid.
It's not very, as you said, sturdy.
It doesn't really seem like it can
stay up in the air for very long.
- And it definitely can't
support someone's weight.
- That's right.
So you can even have a flimsy chair.
Maybe the chair is a little bit looser.
It doesn't seem like it's very strong.
It feels like it might break.
- That's right.
So flimsy, that's the
adjective they're flimsy.
So that's all the adjectives
we have for you today.
Why don't we listen to
the dialogue quickly one
last time and we'd like
to talk a little bit more.
(upbeat music)
- Welcome to Adventure Tours.
How may I help you?
- I want to book a tour
with adventure sports.
- Excellent.
Our company has more
than 10 years of experience
in the Adventure
Tourism and Sports field.
Let me show you some options.
This is our most popular choice.
Our river guides will
take you in a whitewater
rafting trip followed by
a ride in a hot air balloon.
- I don't really think
I'm ready to throw myself
down a river full of jagged
rocks in a rubber boat
or go up in the air in a wicker
basket held up by an oversized balloon.
What else do you have?
- Well, in that case, we can take you hang
gliding with one of our
experienced instructors.
It's the closest you can get to flying.
- What?
- You mean strap myself to a flimsy kite?
- No, thank you.
Next.
- Okay. Well, why don't you tell me a
little bit more about what you would like?
We have everything from mountain
biking to rock climbing to street loose.
- I'm thinking something
exciting, but safer.
- I have the perfect option.
This package will take you on a hiking
trip through the Himalayas for three days.
And afterwards, there's
a dog sledding journey.
That's more like it.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, so Marko, I know this is one
of your favorite areas, adventure sports.
You're a lot more daring
than I am, 'cause I wouldn't
do many of these things,
but what have you done?
- I've actually haven't
been in a hot air balloon.
I don't really think that's very exciting.
It doesn't kind of worry.
- Yeah, you don't really go very fast.
And I've never done a
street luge, luge, which is an
interesting sport, although
it is pretty dangerous.
It's basically you're kind of riding
on a type of skateboard, right?
- Yeah, basically it's a big
skateboard and you lie down on it.
Your feet go down and your head is back.
You're on your back, and
you go downhill really fast.
This is actually an Olympic
sport, and it's simply called luge.
And you can see this with those big icy
tracks that they have, and they go downhill,
and they slide down on a bob sled, or
the luge would actually be the same thing,
but just one or two people on
some type of skateboard looking thing.
- Basically it's open.
The bob sled is closed, so
you see the people's heads in,
but the luge, you just
see their whole body,
and they're lying down on a piece of
metal, and they go down very, very quickly.
- They go very fast.
I think in bob sledding
and luge, I think they can
reach speeds up to like
100 kilometers per hour.
- That's right.
And this year it was actually
very sad at the Olympics.
Luge, I think it was luge,
athlete died in practice.
- That's right.
So extreme sports or adventure sports, they
are, as the name says, full of adventure,
very exciting, but also
obviously very dangerous.
I think hiking is not
really an adventure
sport, or very dangerous,
unless you're hiking
in dangerous territory
with bears or something.
- Possible.
Well, maybe you guys should let us
know what kind of sports do you do?
Do you enjoy adventure sports?
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
- All right, we'll see everyone there.
Bye.
(upbeat music)